<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tgoc-14 on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tags/tgoc-14/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tgoc-14 on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:44:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tags/tgoc-14/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Strathcarron to St Cyrus</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/strathcarron-to-st-cyrus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:41:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/strathcarron-to-st-cyrus/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentally, any route across the Highlands falls into 3 logical parts - the West, between the coast and the Great Glen, the middle between the Great Glen and eastern Cairgorms and the East, which is the bit from Glen Muick/Clova/Ballater to the coast. The middle is the biggest bit as you need to get across two bits of high country - from the Great Glen to the A9 and then across the Cairngorms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mainly Dry with Sunny Intervals and Shattered Showers</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/overview/</guid>
      <description>Challenge blogs from recent years are full of tales of derring-do as Challengers write of their gonad-freezing experiences wading Highland rivers in spate after several days of rain and battling through Monadliath blizzards. Folks experienced black hole of Calcutta conditions as innumerable people crammed into squalid bothies because it was too windy to pitch their tents. The weather, to put it mildly, has been ‘challenging’.
Not this year. Perhaps the best description of the weather in the Highlands this May was benign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photographic Impressions</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/photographic-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/photographic-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I guess that most Challengers take photos of their walk and there are some great landscape photos on Challenger blogs. I’ve been learning about digital photo manipulation recently so I thought that instead of the usual colour pictures, I’d present a more impressionistic view of my Challenge, in monochrome. Some of these I’m pleased with and I think they capture the atmosphere well; others, I’m not so sure.
 Improving weather - Loch Calavie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>