<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aberdeenshire on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tags/aberdeenshire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aberdeenshire on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:57:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tags/aberdeenshire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Deeside Way Guide</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/deeside-way-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 19:57:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/deeside-way-guide/</guid>
      <description>We live right beside the Deeside Way, a walking and riding path that stretches from Aberdeen to Ballater (about 55km). I walk on the Way every week that we are at home and have taken hundreds if not thousands of photographs on these walks.
I decided to set myself a wee project to write a short guide to the Deeside Way that was a bit better than the rather bland description on the official website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Places to finish the Challenge</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/finishing-the-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 15:47:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/finishing-the-challenge/</guid>
      <description>The TGO Challenge is a cross-Scotland walk, starting on the west coast between Ardrishaig and Torridon and ending on the East, between Arbroath and Fraserburgh.
Roger Smith has written an excellent “Essential Guide to Finishing Points” for the TGO Challenge but to slightly misquote Alice in Wonderland: “what is use is a book that has no pictures”. As I’ve visited lots of the places on his list as I’ve wandered up and down the east coast, I thought I’d write a pictorial guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten days, ten walks, ten images</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/ten-ten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:57:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/ten-ten/</guid>
      <description>In this state of lockdown, we are all constrained in where we can travel and who we can meet. We should stay close to home so trips to the hills or the seaside for walking or photography are impossible. I make a point of getting out for a local walk for an hour or so every day so I set myself a wee challenge to chose 10 images taken from 10 walks on consecutive days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glen Dye</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/glen-dye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:49:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/glen-dye/</guid>
      <description>In 2016 there was a proposal to build a 26-turbine windfarm in Glen Dye. I&amp;rsquo;d never been there and I thought that I should have a walk there before the monstrosity was built. I&amp;rsquo;m in favour of renewable energy and wind farms have their place in this. However, I think they should be built in areas of low amenity - not in wild land.
I decided to do a round trip over Clachnaben then from there drop down into Glen Dye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bennachie 2017</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/bennachie-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 22:43:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/bennachie-2017/</guid>
      <description>Rising just over 500 metres from the North-East lowlands, Bennachie is an iconic hills for folks from Aberdeen and the surrounding area. I guess that a large chunk of the population of Aberdeen have been up Bennachie at least once and it has it’s own conservation charity, the Baillies of Bennachie.
It’s about 45 minutes drive from where I live so it’s not exactly a local hill. Nevertheless, I like to try and get up there once or twice a year for the fantastic views.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn Abstractions</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photo-walks/autumn-abstractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:14:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photo-walks/autumn-abstractions/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I went to an interesting talk entitled ‘Art, Photography and Creativity’ by Stan Farrow. Stan talked about the evolution of painting from a representative art to something much more diverse. Painting evolved from explorations of abstract presentations of subjects through to pure abstracts from painters such as Mark Rothko and Jackson Pollock. Stan showed examples of his digital photographic art and how it has developed from purely representative photography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Woods</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photo-walks/a-walk-in-the-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photo-walks/a-walk-in-the-woods/</guid>
      <description>Life has been a wee bit busy this summer (2019). Our daughter gave birth to twins (boy and girl) at the end of July and we&amp;rsquo;ve been involved helping with them and our older grandson since then. Before that, we had decided to move to Edinburgh to be closer to family and, maybe unwisely given that we are no longer spring chickens, bought a house that needs complete renovation. So the summer has been spent working on a house, trying (with no success) to sell a house and helping look after babies and a two-year old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crawton to Catterline 2017</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/crawton-to-catterline-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 13:05:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/crawton-to-catterline-2017/</guid>
      <description>I love coastal walking and, at one time, I thought I might write a guide to the Aberdeenshire coastal path. On paper, this goes from Portsoy to St Cyrus and it should be a fantastic walk. Unfortunately, however, it’s a coastal path in name only and lots of the walk is on roads (even the busy A90) which are a fair bit from the coast. I don’t much like road walking so I’ve given up on this idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunnotar to Skatie Shore 2015</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/dunnotar-to-skatie-shore-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 14:31:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/dunnotar-to-skatie-shore-2015/</guid>
      <description>My well-intentioned idea of using public transport to access the Aberdeenshire coastal path and to walk the path in linear sections has not really worked. Short winter days and infrequent buses mean that too much precious daylight would be spent on or waiting for a bus. So, for this bit of the path, I drove to Stonehaven then walked the sections north and south from there. I’ve written it in the reverse order to my walk so the afternoon photos come first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muchalls to Stonehaven 2015</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/muchalls-to-stonehaven-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 13:49:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/muchalls-to-stonehaven-2015/</guid>
      <description>On the ‘official’ maps of the Aberdeenshire coastal path, there’s a gap between Muchalls and Stonehaven, with the implication that you need to walk along the edge of the busy A90. But my experience is that the ‘official’ maps don’t really reflect the reality on the ground so I thought I would try to see if there was actually a coastal route.
My original idea when walking the coastal path was to do it in sections and use public transport to get to each section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberdeen to Portlethan 2014</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/aberdeen-to-portlethan-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 13:05:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/aberdeen-to-portlethan-2014/</guid>
      <description>The Aberdeenshire Coastal Trail stretches for about 160 miles from Cullen in the north to Montrose in the south. I have walked bits and pieces of it on days out but never in any kind of systematic way. As a national trail, it is not well documented - there are (not very good) maps available from the Aberdeenshire Council website and Gil Campbell has written briefly about it on his blog of walking around the Scottish Coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clachnaben - December 2013</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/clachnaben-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 12:05:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/clachnaben-2013/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the heat that gets to me. My daughters, aided and abetted by their mother, insist on an almost tropical level of heat in the house at Christmas and, after being indoors for Christmas Day, I needed to get out.
So, on the 26th December, whatever the weather, I make a point of going out for a walk somewhere. On this occasiom, we are in the calm between storms and the sky was cloudless at 8am when I got out of bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballater to Aboyne</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/ballater-to-aboyne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 21:43:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/ballater-to-aboyne/</guid>
      <description>The Deeside way is a long distance path that follows the valley of the River Dee from Ballater to Duthie Park in Aberdeen. It mostly follows the old Deeside railway line which was built in the 19th century and which became well-known as Queen Victoria&amp;rsquo;s route to Balmoral Castle. It is a &amp;lsquo;work in progress&amp;rsquo; i.e it isn&amp;rsquo;t finished and there is a gap between Banchory and Potarch Bridge and a shorter gap between Aboyne and Kincardine O&amp;rsquo;Neill.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>