<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinions on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinions on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 17:06:16 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is an electric car the best way to reduce my carbon footprint?</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/petrol-or-electric/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 16:04:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/petrol-or-electric/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts on whether to buy an electric car or a petrol car with carbon offsetting by tree planting.
My car is now 10 years old and has done over 90, 000 miles. It’s starting to show its age and I’ve started thinking about replacing it. I want to do what I can to reduce my personal carbon footprint so I’ve been wondering about an electric car.
Now, of course, you might say just give up your car and travel by public transport (or don’t travel at all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scotland and UBI</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/ubi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 07:58:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/ubi/</guid>
      <description>Should an independent Scotland consider introducing a universal basic income?
During this Coronavirus lockdown. many people, including me, have been posting on blogs and social media about their current or past lifestyle. They write about and share photographs of meals they have cooked, bread they have baked, things they have crafted and walks and holidays they have enjoyed in the past.
A perspective on posts like this that they are middle-class boasting of a lifestyle that many of our fellow citizens do not share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UK has had its day</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/uk-had-its-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:24:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/uk-had-its-day/</guid>
      <description>Why I believe that leaving the EU has the inevitable consequence of the break up of the UK?
I originally wrote this post shortly after the Brexit referendum in 2016. I set why I have changed my views on Scottish independence and why I believe that Scotland should be an independent nation that us part of the EU.
Since then, we have had years of uncertainty, the election of a right-wing, pro-Brexit government and, most significantly a global pandemic that has had immense human, social and economic consequences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highland Spaceports - A Development Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/highland_spaceports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 15:28:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/highland_spaceports/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts on the development of spaceports in environmentally sensitive areas in the Scottish Highlands.
Over the past year or so, the potential of the Scottish Highlands as a suitable area for launching small rockets has been recognised with proposals for development in Sutherland, Shetland and, most recently, North Uist. My twitter feed has been full of retweets recently from outdoor folks asking me to write to the Western Isles Council opposing the North Uist development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signs on the Hills</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/signs-on-the-hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 13:02:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/signs-on-the-hills/</guid>
      <description>Should there be more signposting to reduce navigation mistakes on the hills?
A tweet caught my eye a while ago about a proposal by a mountain rescue team in the Lakes to put signs up on Scafell Pike because so many people are getting lost and then calling out the mountain rescue. The reaction from the mountaineering and backpacking community was predictable outrage. Signs despoil the landscape, remove any feeling of remoteness and encourage people who don’t know what they are doing onto the hills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>