<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edinburgh and the Borders on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edinburgh and the Borders on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:28:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Water of Leith</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/water-of-leith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 11:04:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/water-of-leith/</guid>
      <description>The Water of Leith is a short river that runs from its source in the Pentlands to the Firth of Forth at Leith. There&amp;rsquo;s a path along most of it, starting at Balerno and finishing at Leith. It&amp;rsquo;s about 13 miles (19km) and flat so it&amp;rsquo;s an easy day&amp;rsquo;s walk.
As it&amp;rsquo;s a linear walk, I think it best to use Edinburgh&amp;rsquo;s excellent buses rather than a car to get to the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arthur&#39;s Seat</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/arthurs-seat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 16:07:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/arthurs-seat/</guid>
      <description>Edinburgh is unusual in the it has its own hill called Arthur&amp;rsquo;s Seat close to the centre of the city. It&amp;rsquo;s in Queen&amp;rsquo;s Park, a large green space at the foot of the Royal Mile. I&amp;rsquo;ve walked up Arthur&amp;rsquo;s Seat countless times and in all weathers apart from torrential rain.
 I normally walk up Arthur&#39;s Seat from the west by walking over the Meadows to the Commonwealth swimming pool and then into the park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hillend to Colinton</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/hillend-to-colinton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 14:20:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/hillend-to-colinton/</guid>
      <description>Visiting family in Edinburgh last weekend, Saturday dawned misty and gloomy. My wife and daughters decided to have what they call an ‘Edinburgh Saturday’, which consists of a leisurely lunch, a couple of hours of shopping then cocktails somewhere. I am not at all welcome (thankfully) at such gatherings so I decided that, in spite of the weather, I would get out for a walk somewhere.
One of the great things about walking around Edinburgh is its excellent bus service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seven Hills of Edinburgh</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/seven-hills-of-edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:26:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/seven-hills-of-edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>I said I’d do it and I did. Today, I got started on a training walk for TGOC-2014. This was in an unlikely location - Scotland’s capital. We were in Edinburgh for my daughter’s birthday and I didn’t have the option of a day in the north.
I didn’t have any work today that had to be done, the sun was shining so I thought that I’d do the 7 hills of Edinburgh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Pentland Hills</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/seven_pentland_hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 11:03:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/seven_pentland_hills/</guid>
      <description>Our plans today were to head home from Edinburgh but my wife decided that she&amp;rsquo;s like to go with our daughter to the Ideal Home Show in Glasgow. This did not appeal to me one bit so I had a free day for a wee dauner in the Pentlands. I wrote this post several years ago but I thought it worth preserving as it&amp;rsquo;s a relatively uncommon Pentlands walk.
I decided that, to reflect my walk around the 7 hills of Edinburgh, I would do 7 tops in the Pentlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Wandering</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/city-wandering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 16:41:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/edinburgh/city-wandering/</guid>
      <description>When I get out and about, my first preference is to get to the hills. Unfortunately, family circumstances mean that I can’t get there nearly as often as I’d like so I spend more time daunering in the lowlands rather than the highlands.
So, city walking is not my first preference but it has its own charms. Sometimes this walking is directed (e.g. the seven hills of Edinburgh) but more often than not, I like to wander aimlessly in the city, following unfamiliar streets and paths just to see where I end up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>