<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photography on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photography on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 17:05:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Adobe Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 17:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Adobe Portfolio is a web builder that is part of the Adobe Creative Cloud ecosystem. It is specifically designed to showcase images with the target market being photographers and designers who use the Creative Cloud suite. It isn’t available without a Creative Cloud subscription.
The USP of Adobe Portfolio is that it is integrated with Lightroom, a photo management and editing system that is also part of the Creative Cloud ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography rebooted</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photography-rebooted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 14:56:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photography-rebooted/</guid>
      <description>My photography has taken a back seat for the past couple of years. We have additional family responsibilities (twin grandchildren), we’ve moved from a semi-rural environment near Aberdeen to suburban Edinburgh, we bought a house that needed major work that has dragged on and on and, of course, we’ve been living with COVID restrictions. I’ve had no motivation to take any photographs except family snaps (on my phone) and my camera has not been out of its bag for almost a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten days, ten walks, ten images</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/ten-ten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:57:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/ten-ten/</guid>
      <description>In this state of lockdown, we are all constrained in where we can travel and who we can meet. We should stay close to home so trips to the hills or the seaside for walking or photography are impossible. I make a point of getting out for a local walk for an hour or so every day so I set myself a wee challenge to chose 10 images taken from 10 walks on consecutive days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing With Light</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/drawing-with-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:05:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/drawing-with-light/</guid>
      <description>The word ‘photography’ derives from two Greek roots, which roughly translated mean ‘light’ and ‘to draw’ so photography means ‘drawing with light’. It isn’t ‘copying with light’ because when photography was introduced it did not reproduce what was in front of the camera exactly as seen. Individuals draw the same scene differently, emphasising what is important to them, and until not so long ago, the same was true of photographers - they interpreted and presented what was in front of the camera in quite different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monochrome landscapes</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/monochrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 22:18:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/monochrome/</guid>
      <description>I have been spending more time exploring the possibilities for monochrome images in landscape photography. The problem with colour landscapes, especially in good weather, is that the colours dominate and distract. Sometimes the colours are critical eg. for sunrises and sunsets, but often I think monochrome images are better at communicating an atmosphere and capturing the essence of a place.
 Oxen Craig on Bennachie. Less visited than the main top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/autumn-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 14:30:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/autumn-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Autumn is the most colourful season and, like most outdoor photographers, I love to get out to photograph the landscape at that time of year. Obviously the landscapes are beautiful but I also like to look at a smaller scale for autumn details.
Most of the images here were taken close to my home in Aberdeenshire with a couple on visits to the Highlands.
 River Faskally, near Pitlochry   River Broom near Ullapool with An Teallach in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edinburgh - an alternative view</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 15:32:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>One of the first books of photographs that I bought in the 1970s was entitled &amp;lsquo;Edinburgh&amp;rsquo; by Douglas Corrance. As well as the &amp;lsquo;tourist&amp;rsquo; sights of Edinburgh, Douglas also included more intimate and quirky images that captures the people and details of the places. I really liked this approach and I&amp;rsquo;ve collected here ten images that present an alternative view of Edinburgh from that seen by most tourists to the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iceland</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/iceland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 13:23:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/iceland/</guid>
      <description>Iceland.
What kind of weather comes to mind when you hear the name? I think cold, obviously, snow, rain and cloud. I see monochrome landscapes with volcanic formations emerging from the mist.
But sunshine was what we experienced on two short trips to to Iceland in 2017 and 2018. Not quite wall to wall sunshine - we had some cloudy days and a bit of rain when we went south to Vik.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography or Digital Art</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photography_or_digital_art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 15:11:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/photography_or_digital_art/</guid>
      <description>When I visited Edinburgh last August, I went along to the International Exhibition of the Edinburgh Photographic Society. This is an annual event with over 3000 submissions from across the world and around about 200 acceptances. So it should represent the best of amateur photography.
Yet, when I wandered around the exhibition, I was disappointed. I reckon that at least 50% of the accepted images were ‘Digital art’, created in Photoshop or other image manipulation programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Photography: Sleepwalking into Impermanence</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/sleepwalking_into_impermanence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 15:18:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/myimages/sleepwalking_into_impermanence/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a blog post a while ago which reflected on why we take photographs and some of the problems of digital photography (Alex Roddie: The photos you&amp;rsquo;ll never look at again). This is something that I’ve been thinking about myself and I’m not sure that I’ve come to any definite conclusion. If and when I do, I’ll blog about it.
But, for sure, one reason we take pictures is to capture memories of significant events in our lives - family events, trips and occasions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>