<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The TGO Challenge on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The TGO Challenge on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 17:14:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Scottish Delicacies for TGO Challengers</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/scottish-delicacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 15:47:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/scottish-delicacies/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, I wrote a short guide to some of the Scottish food that Challengers from outwith Scotland may come across. I&amp;rsquo;ve now revised this and turned it into a more general guide in the food section.
Scottish food has a bad reputation but, in the last 15 years or so, it has improved immeasurably, especially in Highland hotels and restaurants. If you eat in a reasonable restaurant, there&amp;rsquo;s every chance you will get a good meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Places to finish the Challenge</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/finishing-the-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 15:47:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/finishing-the-challenge/</guid>
      <description>The TGO Challenge is a cross-Scotland walk, starting on the west coast between Ardrishaig and Torridon and ending on the East, between Arbroath and Fraserburgh.
Roger Smith has written an excellent “Essential Guide to Finishing Points” for the TGO Challenge but to slightly misquote Alice in Wonderland: “what is use is a book that has no pictures”. As I’ve visited lots of the places on his list as I’ve wandered up and down the east coast, I thought I’d write a pictorial guide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>