<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Words on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Words on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 20:43:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Disenchanted with Digital</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/disenchanted_with_digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 12:46:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/disenchanted_with_digital/</guid>
      <description>I started messing around with a camera more than 50 years ago and, then, it was all about black and white film and colour slides. I learned to process film and make prints in the darkroom and I remember the satisfaction of seeing a print emerge in a tray of developer.
Then work and family made all of this practically impossible. We lived in a small house with no room for a darkroom, buying shoes for the baby took precedence over buying Kodachrome and, for many years, my photography was point-and-shoot family snaps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing With Light</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/drawing-with-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 15:05:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/drawing-with-light/</guid>
      <description>The word ‘photography’ derives from two Greek roots, which roughly translated mean ‘light’ and ‘to draw’ so photography means ‘drawing with light’. It isn’t ‘copying with light’ because when photography was introduced it did not reproduce what was in front of the camera exactly as seen. Individuals draw the same scene differently, emphasising what is important to them, and until not so long ago, the same was true of photographers - they interpreted and presented what was in front of the camera in quite different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography or Digital Art</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/photography_or_digital_art/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 15:11:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/photography_or_digital_art/</guid>
      <description>When I visited Edinburgh last August, I went along to the International Exhibition of the Edinburgh Photographic Society. This is an annual event with over 3000 submissions from across the world and around about 200 acceptances. So it should represent the best of amateur photography.
Yet, when I wandered around the exhibition, I was disappointed. I reckon that at least 50% of the accepted images were ‘Digital art’, created in Photoshop or other image manipulation programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Photography: Sleepwalking into Impermanence</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/sleepwalking_into_impermanence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 15:18:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/words/sleepwalking_into_impermanence/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a blog post a while ago which reflected on why we take photographs and some of the problems of digital photography (Alex Roddie: The photos you&amp;rsquo;ll never look at again). This is something that I’ve been thinking about myself and I’m not sure that I’ve come to any definite conclusion. If and when I do, I’ll blog about it.
But, for sure, one reason we take pictures is to capture memories of significant events in our lives - family events, trips and occasions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>