<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TGO Challenge 2018 on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TGO Challenge 2018 on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Shiel Bridge to Johnshaven</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/shiel_bridge_to_johnshaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/shiel_bridge_to_johnshaven/</guid>
      <description>I spent 10 years from 1968 to 1978 stravaiging around the Scottish hills. I was away most weekends climbing or walking and travelled all over the Highlands. Then things changed - family and work - the usual suspects - meant I had less time to get away. I moved away from Scotland for work for almost 20 years and, at best, I managed one or two weekends a year in the Highlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TGOC-2018: Loch Mullardoch</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/loch_mullardoch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/loch_mullardoch/</guid>
      <description>The north shore of Loch Mullardoch is not a Challenge trade route. From Strathcarron, the obvious route west is via Loch Monar and from Shiel Bridge, Glen Affric is the logical route. Mullardoch may be a route from Dornie but it seems that most Dornie starters head for Glen Affric - either via the Falls of Glomach or via Gleann a Choilich at the west end of Loch Mullardoch.
I’d seen Loch Mullardoch from the hills but I’d never been on its shores so I thought it would be an interesting route to try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TGOC-2018: Ten Images</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/ten_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/ten_images/</guid>
      <description>Digital photography is wonderful but it&amp;rsquo;s too easy to take too many pictures. Many of us have computer hard drives with thousands of images. Most of us will never find the time to sort them out.
Because it is so easy to take photographs, some people over-illustrate their accounts of their outdoor adventures. They take lots of pictures so feel the need to include lots of these pictures in their blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TGOC-2018: An Unfortunate Ending</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/an_unfortunate_ending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-18/an_unfortunate_ending/</guid>
      <description>I shouldn’t be writing this post tonight. I should have been on my last wild camp of the 2018 TGO Challenge in Drumtochty forest, finishing tomorrow in Johnshaven. Instead, I’m sitting at home sorting out my photos from the Challenge and wondering if I did the right thing in withdrawing yesterday.
For us baby boomers, morning twinges and muscle stiffness and pains are pretty normal. I’m regularly told to stop the ‘old person noises’ as I stretch and groan to relieve aching joints.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>