<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 13:46:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software engineering education</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/technology/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 13:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/technology/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Some of my thoughts on how we should be teaching students about software engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 13:17:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/technology/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m generally interested in technology, especially but not exclusively digital technologies. I started by writing a blog about systems, software and technology but the problem with blogs is that posts on general issues get lost amongst shorter-term ephemera. I&amp;rsquo;ve now given up on blogging although I still sometimes comment on technology on Twitter (@iansommerville).
The articles here are a selection from my previous technology blog posts plus (very) occasional new articles on technology topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/technology/understanding-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 13:29:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/technology/understanding-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to the Cloud for people who don’t care how it works but want to know how it might be useful for them.
There are basically two ways in which computers are used:
 Personal computers which are used by one person (or sometimes a family) and which can store data, run applications and so on. Shared computers where the computer is shared by a number of different people and which, usually, provide quite specific services.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>