<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coastal path on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tags/coastal-path/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coastal path on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 13:05:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tags/coastal-path/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Crawton to Catterline 2017</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/crawton-to-catterline-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 13:05:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/crawton-to-catterline-2017/</guid>
      <description>I love coastal walking and, at one time, I thought I might write a guide to the Aberdeenshire coastal path. On paper, this goes from Portsoy to St Cyrus and it should be a fantastic walk. Unfortunately, however, it’s a coastal path in name only and lots of the walk is on roads (even the busy A90) which are a fair bit from the coast. I don’t much like road walking so I’ve given up on this idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunnotar to Skatie Shore 2015</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/dunnotar-to-skatie-shore-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 14:31:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/dunnotar-to-skatie-shore-2015/</guid>
      <description>My well-intentioned idea of using public transport to access the Aberdeenshire coastal path and to walk the path in linear sections has not really worked. Short winter days and infrequent buses mean that too much precious daylight would be spent on or waiting for a bus. So, for this bit of the path, I drove to Stonehaven then walked the sections north and south from there. I’ve written it in the reverse order to my walk so the afternoon photos come first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muchalls to Stonehaven 2015</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/muchalls-to-stonehaven-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 13:49:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/muchalls-to-stonehaven-2015/</guid>
      <description>On the ‘official’ maps of the Aberdeenshire coastal path, there’s a gap between Muchalls and Stonehaven, with the implication that you need to walk along the edge of the busy A90. But my experience is that the ‘official’ maps don’t really reflect the reality on the ground so I thought I would try to see if there was actually a coastal route.
My original idea when walking the coastal path was to do it in sections and use public transport to get to each section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberdeen to Portlethan 2014</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/aberdeen-to-portlethan-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 13:05:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/aberdeenshire/aberdeen-to-portlethan-2014/</guid>
      <description>The Aberdeenshire Coastal Trail stretches for about 160 miles from Cullen in the north to Montrose in the south. I have walked bits and pieces of it on days out but never in any kind of systematic way. As a national trail, it is not well documented - there are (not very good) maps available from the Aberdeenshire Council website and Gil Campbell has written briefly about it on his blog of walking around the Scottish Coast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>