<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TGO Challenge 2015 on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TGO Challenge 2015 on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 15:48:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Lochailort to Stonehaven</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/lochailort-to-stonehaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 20:04:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/lochailort-to-stonehaven/</guid>
      <description>I started doing the TGO Challenge - a cross Scotland walk - a couple of years ago. About 300 people of all ages spend a couple of weeks walking from the west coast to the east coast of Scotland. Start points are between Ardrishaig in the south to Torridon in the north and most Challengers finish somewhere between Aberdeen and Montrose.
One of my motivations for taking part in the Challenge was to revisit some of the places that I’d been to many years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Images</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/ten-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 20:43:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/ten-images/</guid>
      <description>Rather than a trip diary, I thought that I&amp;rsquo;d try to sum up my 2015 TGO Challenge in 10 photos. I decided on 10 photos deliberately so that this couldn&amp;rsquo;t just be 1 photo per day - it forced me to be quite ruthless in editing the images I&amp;rsquo;d taken. These are not the 10 best photos that I took - rather, they&amp;rsquo;re the way of capturing what the Challenge was to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Route Reflections</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/route-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 20:43:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/route-reflections/</guid>
      <description>It is now 2 weeks since I got back from the 2015 TGO Challenge, when I walked from Lochailort to Stonehaven. I blogged about my route when I planned it and, more or less, stuck to the planned route. I didn’t do a hill on Day 3 as it was chucking it down so I road-bashed along Loch Arkaig; I took to the forest roads to the south of Loch Rannoch - a longer but less tiring route, and, in spite of a snowstorm, stayed high when travelling east from Mount Keen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>