<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photoblog on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photoblog on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 20:43:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography rebooted</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/photography-rebooted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 14:56:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/photography-rebooted/</guid>
      <description>My photography has taken a back seat for the past couple of years. We have additional family responsibilities (twin grandchildren), we’ve moved from a semi-rural environment near Aberdeen to suburban Edinburgh, we bought a house that needed major work that has dragged on and on and, of course, we’ve been living with COVID restrictions. I’ve had no motivation to take any photographs except family snaps (on my phone) and my camera has not been out of its bag for almost a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten days, ten walks, ten images</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/ten-ten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:57:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/ten-ten/</guid>
      <description>In this state of lockdown, we are all constrained in where we can travel and who we can meet. We should stay close to home so trips to the hills or the seaside for walking or photography are impossible. I make a point of getting out for a local walk for an hour or so every day so I set myself a wee challenge to chose 10 images taken from 10 walks on consecutive days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monochrome landscapes</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/monochrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 22:18:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/monochrome/</guid>
      <description>I have been spending more time exploring the possibilities for monochrome images in landscape photography. The problem with colour landscapes, especially in good weather, is that the colours dominate and distract. Sometimes the colours are critical eg. for sunrises and sunsets, but often I think monochrome images are better at communicating an atmosphere and capturing the essence of a place.
 Oxen Craig on Bennachie. Less visited than the main top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/autumn-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 14:30:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/autumn-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Autumn is the most colourful season and, like most outdoor photographers, I love to get out to photograph the landscape at that time of year. Obviously the landscapes are beautiful but I also like to look at a smaller scale for autumn details.
Most of the images here were taken close to my home in Aberdeenshire with a couple on visits to the Highlands.
 River Faskally, near Pitlochry   River Broom near Ullapool with An Teallach in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untourist Edinburgh</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 15:32:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>One of the first books of photographs that I bought in the 1970s was entitled &amp;lsquo;Edinburgh&amp;rsquo; by Douglas Corrance. As well as the &amp;lsquo;tourist&amp;rsquo; sights of Edinburgh, Douglas also included more intimate and quirky images that captures the people and details of the places. I really liked this approach and I&amp;rsquo;ve collected here ten images that present an alternative view of Edinburgh from that seen by most tourists to the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autumn Abstractions</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/autumn-abstractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:14:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/autumn-abstractions/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I went to an interesting talk entitled ‘Art, Photography and Creativity’ by Stan Farrow. Stan talked about the evolution of painting from a representative art to something much more diverse. Painting evolved from explorations of abstract presentations of subjects through to pure abstracts from painters such as Mark Rothko and Jackson Pollock. Stan showed examples of his digital photographic art and how it has developed from purely representative photography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iceland</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/iceland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 13:23:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/iceland/</guid>
      <description>Iceland.
What kind of weather comes to mind when you hear the name? I think cold, obviously, snow, rain and cloud. I see monochrome landscapes with volcanic formations emerging from the mist.
But sunshine was what we experienced on two short trips to to Iceland in 2017 and 2018. Not quite wall to wall sunshine - we had some cloudy days and a bit of rain when we went south to Vik.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Woods</title>
      <link>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/a-walk-in-the-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansommerville.com/myimages/photoblog/a-walk-in-the-woods/</guid>
      <description>Life has been a wee bit busy this summer (2019). Our daughter gave birth to twins (boy and girl) at the end of July and we&amp;rsquo;ve been involved helping with them and our older grandson since then. Before that, we had decided to move to Edinburgh to be closer to family and, maybe unwisely given that we are no longer spring chickens, bought a house that needs complete renovation. So the summer has been spent working on a house, trying (with no success) to sell a house and helping look after babies and a two-year old.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>