<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Highlands on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tags/highlands/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Highlands on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 13:21:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tags/highlands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Strathcarron to St Cyrus</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/strathcarron-to-st-cyrus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:41:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/strathcarron-to-st-cyrus/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentally, any route across the Highlands falls into 3 logical parts - the West, between the coast and the Great Glen, the middle between the Great Glen and eastern Cairgorms and the East, which is the bit from Glen Muick/Clova/Ballater to the coast. The middle is the biggest bit as you need to get across two bits of high country - from the Great Glen to the A9 and then across the Cairngorms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Lochailort to Stonehaven</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/lochailort-to-stonehaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 20:04:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/lochailort-to-stonehaven/</guid>
      <description>I started doing the TGO Challenge - a cross Scotland walk - a couple of years ago. About 300 people of all ages spend a couple of weeks walking from the west coast to the east coast of Scotland. Start points are between Ardrishaig in the south to Torridon in the north and most Challengers finish somewhere between Aberdeen and Montrose.
One of my motivations for taking part in the Challenge was to revisit some of the places that I’d been to many years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Mallaig to Aberdeen</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/mallaig-to-aberdeen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 20:57:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/mallaig-to-aberdeen/</guid>
      <description>Mallaig to Aberdeen: My original route plan
I start in Mallaig with the Bruce Watt ferry from Mallaig to Knoydart. This has a lot of memories for me as I first went on a Bruce Watt boat (called the Clansman) in the 1950s when I was just a wee boy. I had a shot of driving the boat which was great fun (that&amp;rsquo;s me in the wheelhouse).
  Driving the &#39;Clansman&#39;   I hope to stop at the pub in Inverie for a pint then over the hill to camp at Sourlies bothy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mainly Dry with Sunny Intervals and Shattered Showers</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/overview/</guid>
      <description>Challenge blogs from recent years are full of tales of derring-do as Challengers write of their gonad-freezing experiences wading Highland rivers in spate after several days of rain and battling through Monadliath blizzards. Folks experienced black hole of Calcutta conditions as innumerable people crammed into squalid bothies because it was too windy to pitch their tents. The weather, to put it mildly, has been ‘challenging’.
Not this year. Perhaps the best description of the weather in the Highlands this May was benign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Images</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/ten-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 20:43:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/ten-images/</guid>
      <description>Rather than a trip diary, I thought that I&amp;rsquo;d try to sum up my 2015 TGO Challenge in 10 photos. I decided on 10 photos deliberately so that this couldn&amp;rsquo;t just be 1 photo per day - it forced me to be quite ruthless in editing the images I&amp;rsquo;d taken. These are not the 10 best photos that I took - rather, they&amp;rsquo;re the way of capturing what the Challenge was to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Mallaig to Glen Feshie</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 21:15:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/week-1/</guid>
      <description>Day 1: Mallaig to Sourlies
About 30-odd Challengers set off for Knoydart. Experienced Challengers were chatting; newbies like myself were quieter and a bit apprehensive about what they had let themselves in for. On the ferry, I met Lindsay - a wonderful lady who had her rucksack on what looked like a golf trolley. She told me she&amp;rsquo;d recently had an operation and couldn&amp;rsquo;t carry her rucksack so she had rigged up this trolley to drag it across Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photographic Impressions</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/photographic-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:44:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/photographic-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I guess that most Challengers take photos of their walk and there are some great landscape photos on Challenger blogs. I’ve been learning about digital photo manipulation recently so I thought that instead of the usual colour pictures, I’d present a more impressionistic view of my Challenge, in monochrome. Some of these I’m pleased with and I think they capture the atmosphere well; others, I’m not so sure.
 Improving weather - Loch Calavie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Route Reflections</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/route-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 20:43:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/route-reflections/</guid>
      <description>It is now 2 weeks since I got back from the 2015 TGO Challenge, when I walked from Lochailort to Stonehaven. I blogged about my route when I planned it and, more or less, stuck to the planned route. I didn’t do a hill on Day 3 as it was chucking it down so I road-bashed along Loch Arkaig; I took to the forest roads to the south of Loch Rannoch - a longer but less tiring route, and, in spite of a snowstorm, stayed high when travelling east from Mount Keen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlands</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:29:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of time when I was younger climbing and hill-walking all over the highlands. Nowadays, I wish I could visit more often but I try to visit in spring and autumn as well as getting to the Cairngorms a couple of times a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TGO Challenge 2015</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 15:48:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/</guid>
      <description>I entered the TGO Challenge in 2015 for the third time. My route was from Lochailort to Stonehaven and I came via Loch Rannoch and Blair Atholl rather than the Monadliaths. Great weather to begin with but then very mixed for the rest of the time.
I wrote three blog posts at the time recording my impressions of the crossing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on my Crossing</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/reflections-on-the-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 10:18:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/reflections-on-the-crossing/</guid>
      <description>One of the best bits of advice that I’ve come across about the Challenge was to remember that it’s a holiday, not something to be endured. There is no point in planning an ambitious route if you end up over-tired, injured and miserable. So, my aim was just to have a wee wander across Scotland, without worrying too much about knocking off Munros or covering huge distances in a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day, first Challenge</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/first-day-tgoc13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 13:21:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/first-day-tgoc13/</guid>
      <description>My first Challenge did not start well.
As a newbie, I decided that the most sociable way to start was to catch the &amp;lsquo;Challenger Special&amp;rsquo; from Glasgow to Mallaig and this meant taking a fairly early train from Stonehaven. On our way to the station, I mentally ran through the list of what I should have with me when I realised with horror that I&amp;rsquo;d been messing around with my compass the evening before and had left it on the window ledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cul Mor in the mist</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/culmor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 14:15:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/culmor/</guid>
      <description>Cul Mor and Cul Beag (Mor is Gaelic for big; Beag for small) are easily accessible hills from the road north from Ullapool. I&amp;rsquo;ve climbed them botha couple of times but, sadly, never in good weather. This walk was probably the best - not much rain but thick damp mist on the tops. We had views for about 5 minutes during a brief clearance.
We took the standard route, the path of the A835 by Knockan Crag and then up the shoulder of the hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Hee</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/ben-hee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 15:28:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/ben-hee/</guid>
      <description>We were staying in Ullapool for a mountaineering club dinner and it looked like a typical dreich November day. Low cloud and no sign of a break in the sky. We debated what to do and my pal Dave said that one of the Corbetts that he had still to do was Ben Hee in Sutherland. Others decided on a low-level walk to keep below the clouds but four of us decided to head north to Ben Hee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lochnagar</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/lochnagar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 20:51:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/lochnagar/</guid>
      <description>Mount Keen is the nearest Munro to where we live but it’s a bit of a lump. Lochnagar is the nearest ‘interesting’ hill, which is about 90 minutes drive from our house.
Lochnagar is one of my favourite hills. I first climbed there in the 1970s in the days when I was into winter climbing and I’ve been to the top countless times since then.
 Winter climbing on Black Spout Buttress  This year, I was chatting to our (relatively) new neighbours and discovered that, although natives of Aberdeen, they had never been to the top of Lochnagar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beinn Mor Coigach</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/beinn-mor-coigach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 10:34:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/beinn-mor-coigach/</guid>
      <description>Scotland’s weather is notoriously fickle so when you head for the hills in November, you hope for the best but plan for the worst. Sometimes, the worst happens but sometimes you get one of these unforgettable days on the hill. Typically, you start off in poor weather wondering if you should have taken the ‘sensible’ option of a coastal walk, where you might actually see something. But then the weather improves, the clouds disappear, the landscape emerges and you know that you’ve done the right thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>West Highland Way 2012</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/west-highland-way/whw-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 21:59:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/west-highland-way/whw-2012/</guid>
      <description>I walked the West Highland Way in the first week of May in 2012 as my first long-distance walk after many years where I only had time for day walks. I was concerned about both my fitness and over-crowding on the path. It turned out that I was still fit enough and there were fewer people than I expected. I think starting on a week-day rather than a week-end helped here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highland Spaceports - A Development Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/highland_spaceports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 15:28:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/opinions/highland_spaceports/</guid>
      <description>My thoughts on the development of spaceports in environmentally sensitive areas in the Scottish Highlands.
Over the past year or so, the potential of the Scottish Highlands as a suitable area for launching small rockets has been recognised with proposals for development in Sutherland, Shetland and, most recently, North Uist. My twitter feed has been full of retweets recently from outdoor folks asking me to write to the Western Isles Council opposing the North Uist development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Family Outing on the WHW</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/west-highland-way/whw-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:21:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/west-highland-way/whw-2019/</guid>
      <description>After treatment for a serious illness in 2011, I decided to walk the West Highland Way in 2012 (writeup here) to convince myself that I was still up to multi-day backpacking. I thoroughly enjoyed the experience but I never imagined that I&amp;rsquo;d ever repeat it.
However, 2 or 3 years ago my daughter, Jane, who had never previously shown much interest in outdoors activities, decided that she would like to do the walk and asked if I would do it with her.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>