<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Software Engineering</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Software Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 23:16:26 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software engineering</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/se/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:26:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/se/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 1 and 2 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
Introducing Software Engineering Ten Questions about Software Engineering (*) In this video, I introduce software engineering by answering ten key questions about the discipline covering its nature and the differences between software engineering and other disciplines. Why Software Engineering Matters (*)
In this video, I explain the economic and social importance of software engineering and how it is central to all economic and social developments in the 21st century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile methods</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:26:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/agile/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapter 3 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
Introducing agile development What is agile development (Part 1): What is Agile Development ;
What is agile development (Part 2): An Agile Project Case Study ;
These are a nicely presented introduction to agile development intended for beginners in this area. Genesis Consulting: Agile vs Waterfall
An excellent short video that discusses factors to be considered in deciding if an agile development approach should be adopted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requirements and design</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/req/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:26:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/req/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 4, 5, 6 and 17 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
Requirements engineering An introduction to requirements engineering (*)
In this introductory video I explain what is meant by requirements and requirements engineering. What is a requirement?
This is the first of a series of short, clearly explained requirements engineering videos by a leading RE consultant. You can access other videos by following the links on the YouTube page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iLearn: A digital learning environment</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/ilearn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:37:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/ilearn/</guid>
      <description>In 2012, I was invited to become part of a group developing a specification and architectural design for a digital learning environment for Scottish schools. This came to be called Glow Plus but, in the book, I have called it the iLearn system.
The iLearn system is a digital learning environment used to support learning in schools with students from age 4 to 18. It is intended to replace an existing system (Glow) that was specially built for the purpose and which includes its own applications for e-mail, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 14:30:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/intro/</guid>
      <description>The latest (tenth) edition of my Software Engineering textbook was published in 2015. I have extensively revised and updated the 9th edition to reflect some of the key challenges for software engineering. These are the need for more agile development, the need to manage system complexity and the need to build systems that are secure and resilient. The most important changes are:
 A completely revised chapter on agile methods Self-contained, extensively revised chapters on reliability, safety and security engineering A new chapter on resilience engineering (including cybersecurity) New chapters on systems engineering and systems of systems  As well as this new material, all other chapters have been revised and updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation and evolution</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/imp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:26:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/imp/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 7, 8 and 9 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*). .
Object-oriented design and the UML UML 2.0 video tutorial (Derek Banas)
This is the first of a set of video tutorials that introduce the UML 2.0 notation. You can access the others, that cover the main UML diagram types, from this introduction. Design patterns Design patterns – introduction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical systems</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/critical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:26:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/critical/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapter 10 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
An introduction to critical systems An introduction to critical systems
In this video, I explain what is meant by a critical system and why these are important. Critical systems engineering
In this video, I explain why we need to use more rigorous software engineering methods and techniques when we are developing critical systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentcare: A mental health support system</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/mentcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:38:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/mentcare/</guid>
      <description>This case study focuses on the requirements for a system that I have called the Mentcare system, which is a real system (although that is not its real name) which was used in a number of UK hospitals, including hospitals in Scotland. The system is designed for use in clinics attended by patients suffering from mental health problems and records details of their consultations and conditions. It is separate from a more general patient records system as more detailed information has to be maintained and the system has to be set up to generate letters and reports of different types and to help ensure that the laws pertaining to mental health are maintained by staff treating patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliability and safety</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/reliability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:27:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/reliability/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 11 and 12 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
Software reliability and availability Availability and reliability (*)
This video explains what availability and reliability means in critical systems. Airbus FCS – software and hardware redundancy (*)
In this video, I explain how software and hardware redundancy is used to achieve high reliability and availability in the safety-critical flight control system in the Airbus 340.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security and resilience</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:27:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/security/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 13 and 14 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
System security System security (*)
This video explains what system security is and its relationship with other dependability attributes.  Security is a sociotechnical issue (*)
This video explains why technical approaches are not enough to deal with the problems of cybersecurity and why it is essential to view cybersecurity as a sociotechnical issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal insulin pump</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/insulin-pump/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:37:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/insulin-pump/</guid>
      <description>This case study discusses the control software for a personal insulin pump, which is used by diabetics to mimic the function of the pancreas and hence control the level of glucose (sugar) in their blood. The system hardware is illustrated schematically in the following diagram:
 &amp;nbsp; The level of blood sugar depends on what the system user has eaten, the speed of their digestive processes and the effectiveness of their body in metabolising blood sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instructor&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/instructors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 14:29:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/instructors/</guid>
      <description>Rather than include the instructor’s guide as web pages, I have created a number of downloadable documents that discuss different ways of using the book in teaching. Some of these are freely available, others can only be accessed with credentials from Pearson Education.
Ideas for using the book in teaching Every course is different and what’s included depends on the interests of the instructor, the background of the students, the type of software being discussed and the resources available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software reuse</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/reuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:27:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/reuse/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 15, 16 and 18 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
Software reuse The reuse landscape (*)
In this video, I introduce the wide range of ways in which software can be reused. Introduction to Web Application Frameworks
Introduces a number of web application frameworks although he doesn’t really say a great deal about what these actually are. Software Product Line Engineering</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems engineering</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:27:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/systems/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 19 to 21 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
Systems engineering Introducing sociotechnical systems (*)
In this video, I introduce the idea of sociotechnical systems and explains the differences between sociotechnical and technical systems. Emergent properties of sociotechnical systems (*)
This video discusses the key emergent properties of sociotechnical systems. System success and failure (*)
In this video, I discuss how the notions of success and failure are not absolute for sociotechnical systems but depend on the judgment of the system user or observer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A wilderness weather station</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:38:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/weather/</guid>
      <description>This case study is based on the software for a wilderness weather station that collects weather information in remote areas that do not have local infrastructure (power, communications, roads, etc.). These weather stations are part of a national weather information system that is intended to capture and analyse detailed weather information to help understand both local and national climate change and to support the national weather forecasting service.
The important characteristic of the weather station is that it has to be entirely self-contained as power and communications are not available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 14:29:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/slides/</guid>
      <description>The links below are links to the slideshare presentations for each chapter of the book. You can view the presentation or download it from slideshare. There is also a link from which you can download Powerpoint presentations for all chapters as a zip file.
   Chap 1   Chap 2   Chap 3   Chap 4   Chap 5      Chap 6   Chap 7   Chap 8   Chap 9   Chap 10      Chap 11   Chap 12   Chap 13   Chap 14   Chap 15      Chap 16   Chap 17   Chap 18   Chap 19   Chap 20      Chap 21   Chap 22   Chap 23   Chap 24   Chap 25        &amp;nbsp;  Download zip file of PPTX slides for all chapters </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software management</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:27:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/videos/management/</guid>
      <description>These videos support the material in Chapters 19, 20 and 21 in the 10th edition of Software Engineering. My videos are starred (*).
Project management Why software project management is different?
A video that explains why software project management differs from other types of project management. I don’t agree with everything she says but she is right that there are important differences. Risk management fundamentals
This is quite a nice introduction to risk management although I find the chalkboard presentation style to be a bit irritating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airbus 340 flight control system</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/airbus340/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:37:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/airbus340/</guid>
      <description>This case study describes the architecture of the Airbus 340 flight control system, a safety critical system that implements the fly-by-wire flight system on the Airbus.
The Airbus A340 is a long-haul aircraft that includes a critical fly-by-wire flight control system that mediates pilot commands and controls flight surface actuators. This is a development of the first fly-by-wire system which was introduced in the Airbus A320 aircraft. It is of particular interest because of the approach used for hardware and software redundancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplements</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 12:35:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/downloads/</guid>
      <description>I have designed my textbook to be a hybrid print-web book and the supplements here provide additional information over and above what is included in the printed text.
Sample chapters Sample chapters are complete chapters from the book that you can download to get an impression of the book&amp;rsquo;s contents.
[Chapter 1 Introduction](href=&amp;quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/b8u3j74fkigb5vd/Ch01%20Introduction.pdf?dl=0&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;) [Ch 12 Safety Engineering](https://www.dropbox.com/s/9vvgmn7x6w6uit4/Ch%2012%20Safety%20Engineering.pdf?dl=0&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;) [Systems of systems](https://www.dropbox.com/s/xo80lb1rvwtzd1e/Ch%2020%20Systems%20of%20systems.pdf?dl=0&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank)  Web chapters Web chapters are chapters that have been included in previous editions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ariane 5 launch accident</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/ariane5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:38:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/case-studies/ariane5/</guid>
      <description>This case study describes the accident that occurred on the initial launch of the Ariane 5 rocket, a launcher developed by the European Space Agency. The rocket exploded shortly after take-off and the subsequent enquiry showed that this was due to a fault in the software in the inertial navigation system.
In June 1996, the then new Ariane 5 rocket was launched on its maiden flight. It carried a payload of scientific satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My sites</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/mysites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 13:08:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/mysites/</guid>
      <description>As well as this site, I have two other websites.
Images and Opinions, which is my personal site that includes information about my interests and my professional career.
Engineering Software Products in which I take a different approach to introductory software engineering. The focus is on engineering software products rather than engineering software systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Sections</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/web-sections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 09:34:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/web-sections/</guid>
      <description>These links display the web section in a new browser window. To keep a copy of the web section, use your browser to save it as PDF.
   history of software engineering (1)        spiral model (2)   incremental development problems (2)   software tools (2)      feasibility study (4)   domain requirements  (4)   viewpoints (4)      natural language requirements (4)   requirements standards (4)   requirements reviews (4)      changing requirements (4)   traceability (4)      UML (5)   data-flow diagrams  (5)   executable UML (5)      architecture patterns (6)   application architecture (6)   reference architecture (6)      weather station use cases (7)   deployment (7)      test planning (8)   debugging (8)   path testing  (8)      integration (8)        program evolution dynamics (9)        critical systems (10)   ariane 5 failure  (10)   human error (10)      over-specifying reliability (11)   error-prone constructs (11)   reliability growth modeling (11)      risk-driven specification (12)   safety licensing (12)       denial of service attacks (13)        cbse problems (16)   components and objects  (16)       corba (16)        l egacy services (18)        real-time java  (21)        p-cmm (22)   people selection (22)   workspace  (22)      planning activities (23)   overhead costs (23)   productivity (23)      COCOMO cost drivers  (23)        documentation standards (24)   QM roles  (24)       agile changes (25)               </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes from the 9th edition</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/changes9th/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:20:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/changes9th/</guid>
      <description>In summary, the major updates and additions in this book from the 9th edition are:
I have extensively updated the chapter on agile software engineering, with new material on Scrum. I have updated other chapters as required to reflect the increasing use of agile methods of software engineering. I have added new chapters on resilience engineering, systems engineering and systems of systems. I have completely reorganized three chapters covering reliability, safety and security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errata</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/errata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 15:07:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/software-engineering-book/errata/</guid>
      <description>A small number of minor errors have been discovered since the book was published.
Chapter 2, page 31, 6. The word ‘Professional’ should be deleted.
Chapter 6: page 158, Line 11. Replace questions 4 to 6 with &amp;lsquo;on architectural style, system structuring and control strategy&amp;rsquo;.
Chapter 8, page 222, line 4. ‘eight’ should be replaced by ‘ten’
Chapter 11, page 310. line 15, &amp;lsquo;reliability&amp;rsquo; (last word in line) should be replaced by &amp;lsquo;POFOD&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>