<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My First TGO Challenge (2013) on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My First TGO Challenge (2013) on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 15:47:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Mallaig to Aberdeen</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/mallaig-to-aberdeen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 20:57:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/mallaig-to-aberdeen/</guid>
      <description>Mallaig to Aberdeen: My original route plan
I start in Mallaig with the Bruce Watt ferry from Mallaig to Knoydart. This has a lot of memories for me as I first went on a Bruce Watt boat (called the Clansman) in the 1950s when I was just a wee boy. I had a shot of driving the boat which was great fun (that&amp;rsquo;s me in the wheelhouse).
  Driving the &#39;Clansman&#39;   I hope to stop at the pub in Inverie for a pint then over the hill to camp at Sourlies bothy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Mallaig to Glen Feshie</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 21:15:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/week-1/</guid>
      <description>Day 1: Mallaig to Sourlies
About 30-odd Challengers set off for Knoydart. Experienced Challengers were chatting; newbies like myself were quieter and a bit apprehensive about what they had let themselves in for. On the ferry, I met Lindsay - a wonderful lady who had her rucksack on what looked like a golf trolley. She told me she&amp;rsquo;d recently had an operation and couldn&amp;rsquo;t carry her rucksack so she had rigged up this trolley to drag it across Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Glen Feshie to Aberdeen</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:20:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/week-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 8: Glen Feshie to Mar Lodge
I woke up to cloud but the weather looked set to improve as I set off - as ever, I was not early and a few Challengers had already passed me although they had stayed at the bothy or camped further down the glen. The upper part of the Glen is not as attractive as the more wooded lower Glen Feshie and, after crossing the watershed, the path was pretty boggy and a wee bit dull.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day, first Challenge</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/first-day-tgoc13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 13:21:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/first-day-tgoc13/</guid>
      <description>My first Challenge did not start well.
As a newbie, I decided that the most sociable way to start was to catch the &amp;lsquo;Challenger Special&amp;rsquo; from Glasgow to Mallaig and this meant taking a fairly early train from Stonehaven. On our way to the station, I mentally ran through the list of what I should have with me when I realised with horror that I&amp;rsquo;d been messing around with my compass the evening before and had left it on the window ledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>