<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Highlands on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Highlands on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 13:29:04 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cul Mor in the mist</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/culmor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 14:15:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/culmor/</guid>
      <description>Cul Mor and Cul Beag (Mor is Gaelic for big; Beag for small) are easily accessible hills from the road north from Ullapool. I&amp;rsquo;ve climbed them botha couple of times but, sadly, never in good weather. This walk was probably the best - not much rain but thick damp mist on the tops. We had views for about 5 minutes during a brief clearance.
We took the standard route, the path of the A835 by Knockan Crag and then up the shoulder of the hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben Hee</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/ben-hee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 15:28:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/ben-hee/</guid>
      <description>We were staying in Ullapool for a mountaineering club dinner and it looked like a typical dreich November day. Low cloud and no sign of a break in the sky. We debated what to do and my pal Dave said that one of the Corbetts that he had still to do was Ben Hee in Sutherland. Others decided on a low-level walk to keep below the clouds but four of us decided to head north to Ben Hee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lochnagar</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/lochnagar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 20:51:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/lochnagar/</guid>
      <description>Mount Keen is the nearest Munro to where we live but it’s a bit of a lump. Lochnagar is the nearest ‘interesting’ hill, which is about 90 minutes drive from our house.
Lochnagar is one of my favourite hills. I first climbed there in the 1970s in the days when I was into winter climbing and I’ve been to the top countless times since then.
 Winter climbing on Black Spout Buttress  This year, I was chatting to our (relatively) new neighbours and discovered that, although natives of Aberdeen, they had never been to the top of Lochnagar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beinn Mor Coigach</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/beinn-mor-coigach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 10:34:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/highlands/beinn-mor-coigach/</guid>
      <description>Scotland’s weather is notoriously fickle so when you head for the hills in November, you hope for the best but plan for the worst. Sometimes, the worst happens but sometimes you get one of these unforgettable days on the hill. Typically, you start off in poor weather wondering if you should have taken the ‘sensible’ option of a coastal walk, where you might actually see something. But then the weather improves, the clouds disappear, the landscape emerges and you know that you’ve done the right thing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>