<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tgoc on Images and Opinions</title>
    <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tags/tgoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tgoc on Images and Opinions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 13:21:09 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iansomme.github.io/tags/tgoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My route: Lochailort to Stonehaven</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/lochailort-to-stonehaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 20:04:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/lochailort-to-stonehaven/</guid>
      <description>I started doing the TGO Challenge - a cross Scotland walk - a couple of years ago. About 300 people of all ages spend a couple of weeks walking from the west coast to the east coast of Scotland. Start points are between Ardrishaig in the south to Torridon in the north and most Challengers finish somewhere between Aberdeen and Montrose.
One of my motivations for taking part in the Challenge was to revisit some of the places that I’d been to many years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Images</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/ten-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 20:43:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/ten-images/</guid>
      <description>Rather than a trip diary, I thought that I&amp;rsquo;d try to sum up my 2015 TGO Challenge in 10 photos. I decided on 10 photos deliberately so that this couldn&amp;rsquo;t just be 1 photo per day - it forced me to be quite ruthless in editing the images I&amp;rsquo;d taken. These are not the 10 best photos that I took - rather, they&amp;rsquo;re the way of capturing what the Challenge was to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Route Reflections</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/route-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 20:43:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/route-reflections/</guid>
      <description>It is now 2 weeks since I got back from the 2015 TGO Challenge, when I walked from Lochailort to Stonehaven. I blogged about my route when I planned it and, more or less, stuck to the planned route. I didn’t do a hill on Day 3 as it was chucking it down so I road-bashed along Loch Arkaig; I took to the forest roads to the south of Loch Rannoch - a longer but less tiring route, and, in spite of a snowstorm, stayed high when travelling east from Mount Keen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TGO Challenge 2015</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 15:48:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-15/</guid>
      <description>I entered the TGO Challenge in 2015 for the third time. My route was from Lochailort to Stonehaven and I came via Loch Rannoch and Blair Atholl rather than the Monadliaths. Great weather to begin with but then very mixed for the rest of the time.
I wrote three blog posts at the time recording my impressions of the crossing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guide to Scottish Delicacies for TGO Challengers</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/scottish-delicacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 15:47:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/scottish-delicacies/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, I wrote a short guide to some of the Scottish food that Challengers from outwith Scotland may come across. I&amp;rsquo;ve now revised this and turned it into a more general guide in the food section.
Scottish food has a bad reputation but, in the last 15 years or so, it has improved immeasurably, especially in Highland hotels and restaurants. If you eat in a reasonable restaurant, there&amp;rsquo;s every chance you will get a good meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on my Crossing</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/reflections-on-the-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 10:18:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-14/reflections-on-the-crossing/</guid>
      <description>One of the best bits of advice that I’ve come across about the Challenge was to remember that it’s a holiday, not something to be endured. There is no point in planning an ambitious route if you end up over-tired, injured and miserable. So, my aim was just to have a wee wander across Scotland, without worrying too much about knocking off Munros or covering huge distances in a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Places to finish the Challenge</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/finishing-the-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 15:47:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/finishing-the-challenge/</guid>
      <description>The TGO Challenge is a cross-Scotland walk, starting on the west coast between Ardrishaig and Torridon and ending on the East, between Arbroath and Fraserburgh.
Roger Smith has written an excellent “Essential Guide to Finishing Points” for the TGO Challenge but to slightly misquote Alice in Wonderland: “what is use is a book that has no pictures”. As I’ve visited lots of the places on his list as I’ve wandered up and down the east coast, I thought I’d write a pictorial guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day, first Challenge</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/first-day-tgoc13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 13:21:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/tgoc/tgoc-13/first-day-tgoc13/</guid>
      <description>My first Challenge did not start well.
As a newbie, I decided that the most sociable way to start was to catch the &amp;lsquo;Challenger Special&amp;rsquo; from Glasgow to Mallaig and this meant taking a fairly early train from Stonehaven. On our way to the station, I mentally ran through the list of what I should have with me when I realised with horror that I&amp;rsquo;d been messing around with my compass the evening before and had left it on the window ledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The TGO Challenge</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/tgoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 10:13:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/walks/tgoc/</guid>
      <description>The TGO Challenge is an annual event where people walk across Scotland from the west to the east coast. They choose their own route and there are various meeting points, such as Braemar, where participants congregate. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken part in this 4 times (so far) and I hope to be able to do a few more.
I&amp;rsquo;ve documented my Challenges under a separate heading.
The TGO Challenge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scottish Delicacies</title>
      <link>https://iansomme.github.io/foodpages/scottish-delicacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 15:43:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iansomme.github.io/foodpages/scottish-delicacies/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this short guide to some &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; Scottish food and drink for people planning a TGO Challenge - a cross country walk across Scotland, which I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few times. However, I think it may be of more general interest so I&amp;rsquo;ve extended it a wee bit and put it in the more general food section rather than the TGOC pages.
I won’t write here about the excellent ‘high-end’ Scottish food such as venison and langoustines, that you might get in restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>